Baylor Scott and white physicians
we just had Match Day
we're talking about the physician loan versus new builder incentives
so if you got match with Baylor
Scott and white and you're moving to temple
you're looking for kind of a first time home here
here we're in the Pecan Ridge new construction neighborhood
they're building up homes here
the builder incentives are just blowing the
all of the rest of the competition out of the water
so this particular uh
neighborhood is Dr Horton
they're offering 3.99% fixed rate for 30 years
I just had clients get in
3.99% and they also got a 2 1 buy down
so the deal with the physician loan
is that they're not going to accept that
and still give you the incentive
you can get flex cash but you're not going to get Lind
the preferred lender incentives for from the builder
so how does that compare
the biggest difference between the FHA and then the physician loan
is that the physician loan
you do not have to put anything down
zero down payment no PMI
the FHA you need about 3.5% down
and you're gonna have PMI
but on like this home
I think this is gonna be around like the 2 32 50 range
that's there's still a 350 dollar difference
between physician loan and the builder incentive loan
and the builder incentive is the better payment
the other thing that really stood out to me for doctors residents
that are going to Baylor Scott and white
is that you get into one of these homes
you're going to be able to grow in it for the first three four
five years and then you can
you can just sell it and move on
the PMI is not going to make a huge difference
but what does make a huge difference is the first year
whenever your salary is inevitably lower
than what it's going to be for the rest of your career
you can get like
my client got a 2 1 buy down on this
so it's 1.99% for the very first year
2.99% for the second year
and then 3.99 for the third and the rest of the years
so it really gives you a lot more freedom
with the monthly payment as opposed to a physician loan
where you're not gonna have to put anything down
but you're gonna have a significantly higher payment
you know by at least $350
the other thing is like it
I can see kind of an objection
like with the FHA builder uh
lender with the down payment
the crazy thing so stylecraft
you're not gonna you gotta pick one or the other right
the interest rate or the flex cash Dr
Horton though
they pay most of your closing cost
and here's what I'm doing for my client
they're having to come with
like 15 dollars for closing cost to the table
I'm just gonna cut my commission
I showed them one day and got them into a great property
exactly what they're looking for
I said look
I didn't have to do a whole bunch of stuff
I'll I got you
so if it's something like that
I'm happy to hook you up there is the
there's a kind of a pros and cons
but listen the physician loan
now whenever you get into
let's say you want something a little bit more custom
you don't wanna get into the basic
uh home
a basic new build
cookie cutter home and you want something custom
and you are okay with the extra monthly payment
the physician loan
I think is a great option for you if you're doing resale
it's very it's almost the same as having a VA loan really
you get no PMI you get no down payment
the loan criteria to to be approved
it works with your your career moving up
so they take what you're going to make
they they don't just analyze you
and they also don't
there's something that they do with the student loans
that improves how it looks like
they're not gonna count the student loans against you
or they're not going to count too much against you
which one is the best for you specifically
I will say right now if you were looking at any new builder community
go with the lender incentives by the builder
they're gonna get a better interest rate
the most if the most important thing is
you know the financial aspect
and it really for a lot of these people it
it is because they know they're gonna be there for a while
it's a good idea to buy something and then be able to capitalize on
you know the equity
the principal pay down
and it the
the numbers just work better in terms of risk as well
uh with one of these
like on these homes
you can I ran the numbers for this guy
he could literally rent the place out in cash flow by
with putting 3.5% down so the other option
the other thing that I ran into is
let's say you this is your first job
you know you've been in school all this time
you don't have anything saved up
FHA you can get a gift from your parents
you can get gift funds and you can use that
and a lot of the times
especially if your parents already saw you grinding it out
through all of that school
they will want to get you set up to where
you can then capitalize on all of the other benefits of owning a home
pretty much like a wide overview of both of these
but from experience I
I will say that getting these builder lender incentives
is gonna be the number one thing
that you can do for yourself in the future
and then you have so many more options whenever you do that
and you have a low interest rate
you got a safe you know
asset in a good area
if you're a physician reach out to me
I'm going to get you and everybody is different
I'm gonna get you set up on exactly what works best for your goals
I'm gonna give you pros and cons of each scenario
and you can decide with my guidance alright
call me text me
email me
schedule an appointment with me down below if you're moving to temple
I hope you all enjoy this video let's get it